Wilson, R. A. mss. II, 1967-1979 LMC 2583
Lilly Library
Wilson, R. A. mss. II
1967-1979
Lilly Library
Wilson, Robert A. (Robert Alfred), 1922-2016
Phoenix Book Shop
Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972
Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973
Ashbery, John, 1927-2017
Wilbur, Richard, 1921-2017
Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley), 1927-2019
Nemerov, Howard
Duncan, Robert, 1919-1988
Snyder, Gary, 1930-
McClure, Michael
Wieners, John, 1934-2002
Reynolds, Tim
Zukofsky, Louis, 1904-1978
Corso, Gregory
Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997
Orlovsky, Peter, 1933-2010
Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979
Merrill, James, 1926-1995
Di Prima, Diane
Kinnell, Galway, 1927-2014
Baraka, Amiri, 1934-2014
LMC 2583
2 Boxes 2 standard
The Wilson, R. A. mss. II, 1967-1979, consist of three albums of documents pertaining to the Oblong Octavo series published by R. A. Wilson of the Phoenix Book Shop.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift: 2007
Biographical Note
Robert Alfred Jump Wilson, 1922-2016, was a bookseller who owned Phoenix Book Shop in New York from 1962-1988. Wilson received a B.A. in English and American Literature from Johns Hopkins University in 1943, then joined the Army followed by the diplomatic corps. He worked briefly as a translator at the Nuremberg war crimes trials.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of three albums containing documents pertaining to the Oblong Octavo series, which consisted of twenty signed limited-edition publications. The Series began in 1967 to "help Marianne Moore who had told [Wilson] she was devastated by the New Yorker's refusal of a poem which she had counted on for income." The next work in the series featured Wilson's longtime friend W. H. Auden, followed by Ashbery, Wilbur, Merwin, Nemerov, Duncan, Snyder, McClure, Wiebers, Tim Reynolds, Zukofsky, Corso, Ginsberg, Orlovsky, Bishop, Merrill, di Primar, Kinnell & Baraka. All author files include correspondence, manuscripts, proofs, and related material.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by work.
Related Materials
See Wilson, R. A. mss. and Phoenix Book Shop mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Publishers and publishing; Booksellers and bookselling; Phoenix Book Shop oblong octavo series
- Oblong Octavo Series
  - Ashbury, John "Sunrise in Suburbia", 1968 (Box 1)
  - Auden, W. H. "Two Songs", 1968 (Box 1)
  - Amiri, Baraka "Am/Track", 1979 (Box 1)
  - Bishop, Elizabeth "Poem", 1973 (Box 1)
  - Corso, Gregory "☥", 1971 (Box 1)
  - Duncan, Robert "Achillies", 1969 (Box 1)
  - Di Prima, Diane "Loba as Eve", 1975 (Box 1)
  - Ginsburg, Allen "New Year Blues", 1972 (Box 1)
  - Kinnell, Galway "Three Poems", 1976 (Box 1)
  - McClure, Michael "Plane Pomes", 1969 (Box 1)
  - Merrill, James "Yannina", 1973 (Box 1)
  - Merwin, W.S. "Three Poems", 1968 (Box 1)
  - Moore, Marianne "Tipoo's Tiger", 1967 (Box 1)
  - Nemerov, Howard "The Painter Dreaming in the Scholars House", 1968 (Box 2)
  - Orlovsky, Peter "Leper's Cry", 1972 (Box 2)
  - Reynolds, Tim "Tlatelolco: A Sequence from Que", 1970 (Box 2)
  - Snyder, Gary "The Blue Sky", 1969 (Box 2)
  - Wieners, John "Youth", 1970 (Box 2)
  - Wilbur, Richard "Complaint", 1968 (Box 2)
  - Zukofsky, Louis "Initial", 1970 (Box 2)
- Correspondence and Related Materials
  - Ashbury, John, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Auden, William, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Baraka Amiri, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Corso Gregory, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Di Prima, Diane, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Duncan, Robert, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Ginsburg, Allen, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Kinnell, Galway, 1975 (Box 1)
  - McClure, Michael, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Merrill, James, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Merwin, W.S., 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Nemerov, Howard, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Orlovsky, Peter, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Reynolds, Tim, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Snyder, Gary, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Wieners, John, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Wilbur, Richard, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Zukofsky, Louis, 1970 (Box 2)